Class of 1900 Records, 1896-1965
Smith College Archives
Class of 1900 Records
1896-1965
Smith College. Class of 1900.
RG 80 UUID:496d0b9b-d107-4f87-8faa-372d0c521119
13 boxes (7.3 linear ft.)
Smith College Archives Northampton, MA
This collection is in 13 boxes and contains photographs, invitations, songs, newspaper clippings, and other memorabilia from the commencement and reunions of the Class of 1900.
Historical Note
The Class of 1900 was the twenty-second entering class and the twenty-second graduating class of Smith College.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Class of 1900 records, 1896-1965, contain materials describing the history and activities of the Class of 1900, including materials from commencement, reunions, senior dramatics, and other important events. Types of materials include photographs, invitations, songs, newspaper clippings, letters, photo albums, and other memorabilia.
Individual biographical files are also available, and often include photographs, photo albums, newspaper clippings, letters and correspondences, and class notes.
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The records are open for research according to the regulations of the Smith College Archives without any additional restrictions.
History of the Collection
The Class of 1900 records were created by the students and donated to the College Archives.
- Class Baby 1915-1922 (Box 1581, Folder 1)
- Baccalaureate 1900 (Box 1581, Folder 2)
- Clipping Book from Smith Alumnae Quarterly 1922-1948 (Box 1581, Folder 3)
- Commencement 1900 (Box 1581, Folder 4)
- Commencement Music 1900 (Box 1581, Folder 5)
- Commencement Photographs 1900 (Box 1581, Folder 6)
- Class Day 1900 (Box 1581, Folder 7)
- Freshman Grind by 1899 1896 (Box 1581, Folder 8)
- Groups 1896-1900 (Box 1581, Folder 9)
- Class History 1897-1900 (Box 1581, Folder 10)
- Ivy Day 1900 (Box 1581, Folder 11)
- Ivy Day Photographs 1900 (Box 1581, Folder 12)
- Junior Frolic 1899 (Box 1581, Folder 13)
- Junior Prom 1899 (Box 1581, Folder 14)
- Junior Prom Programs 1899 (Box 1581, Folder 15)
- Junior-Senior Entertainment 1899 (Box 1581, Folder 16)
- Junior Ushers 1899 (Box 1581, Folder 17)
- Class Letters 1916-1962 (Box 1581, Folder 18)
- Place Cards and Tabs n.d. (Box 1581, Folder 19)
- Class Ribbon 1950 (Box 1582, Folder 1)
- Seal, Emblem, Stationery, etc n.d. (Box 1582, Folder 2)
- Class Secretary- Correspondence 1969, 1951, 1934 (Box 1582, Folder 3)
- Class Secretary- Minutes 1896-1960 (Box 1582, Folder 4)
- Songs n.d. (Box 1582, Folder 5)
- Sophomore Reception 1896 (Box 1582, Folder 6)
- Class Supper 1900 (Box 1582, Folder 7)
- Class Treasurer 1950-1960 (Box 1582, Folder 8)
- Senior Dramatics 1900 (Box 1582.1, Folder 1)
- Senior Dramatics: Photographs (Box 1582.1, Folder 2)
- Senior Dramatics: Photograph Album 1900 (Box 1582.1, Folder 3)
- Senior Dramatics: Photograph Album 1900 (Box 1582.1, Folder 4)
- Reunions n.d. (Box 1583, Folder 1)
- Reunion Songs n.d. (Box 1583, Folder 2)
- Reunions 1901-1903 (Box 1583, Folder 3)
- Reunions 1910 (Box 1583, Folder 4)
- Reunions 1915 (Box 1583, Folder 5)
- Reunions 1920 (Box 1583, Folder 6)
- Reunions 1925 (Box 1583, Folder 7)
- Reunions 1930 (Box 1583, Folder 8)
- Reunions 1935 (Box 1583, Folder 9)
- Reunions 1940 (Box 1583, Folder 10)
- Reunions 1945 (Box 1583, Folder 11)
- Reunions 1950 (Box 1583, Folder 12)
- Reunions 1955 (Box 1583, Folder 13)
- Reunions 1965 (Box 1583, Folder 14)
- Reunion Register 1920-1940 (Box 1583, Folder 15)